<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hackaton on My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo</title>
    <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/tags/hackaton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hackaton on My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 19:58:33 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://deilanexe.github.io/tags/hackaton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GovHack 2016 (Little Steps aka MOLE)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/govhack__mole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 19:58:33 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/govhack__mole/</guid>
      <description>This project will develop a prototype, responsive and visually simple website that can help newly arrived migrants, refugees and asylum seekers navigate the complexities of settlement in Australia and connect to communities.
As part of the team I was in charge of extracting information from different data sources, which also involved diverse formats like CSV, plain text and JSON. Also I implemented an API in Python Flask that was used to query and return information from our consolidated data source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular 2 Hack (hosted by General Assembly &amp; SSW)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/angular_2_hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/angular_2_hack/</guid>
      <description>I participated in this half-a-day crash-course hosted by General Assembly to learn the basics on Angular 2. Given that what-to-wear was a personal project already running in AngularJS, me and my friend Mardi decided to work towards starting its migration to Angular 2. We struggled a bit to make it work and reducing dependencies towards using PHP (which set the basis for developing the what-to-wear API project).
We ended up sharing the top prize as shown here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RHoK: Changing Places (Jun 2016)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/rhok__jun_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/rhok__jun_2016/</guid>
      <description>Random Hacks of Kindness is &amp;ldquo;a community of technologists who solve problems for purpose driven organisations&amp;rdquo;. In the Winter 2016 2-day hackaton, I joined the team &amp;ldquo;Changing Places&amp;rdquo;, which had the following tasks:
 completing their WordPress website; and, proposing new ways for users to interact with them.  I got involved in the second task, and proposed different approaches for fast communication under the assumption that many carers carry a smart phone with them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>