<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo on My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo</title>
    <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo on My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 12:13:35 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>SQUAT II (Jul 2016-Present)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/SQUAT_II/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/SQUAT_II/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Search Quality Assessment Tool, or SQUAT, is an internally-developed
framework where search analysts can debug queries to their search platform. In
SQUAT, analysts create &lt;em&gt;gold sets&lt;/em&gt;, which are collections of user &lt;em&gt;queries&lt;/em&gt; with
a set of expected results, also called &lt;em&gt;expectations&lt;/em&gt;. In its second
implementation, SQUAT enables map-based search, gold set result comparisons, and
an API to connect to that provides the endpoints required to operate these
functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my contribution to SQUAT II, I got involved with the redesign of the
user interface, including some of the functional components such as the creation
of gold sets and importing/exporting gold sets into and from spreadsheets for
easy operation outside of the tool. I was also in charge of documenting cards for an offshore
developer who is in charge of implementing these changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQUAT II is likely to have a release outside of Sensis sometime during 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizon Zero Dawn</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/Horizon_Zero_Dawn__PS4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/Horizon_Zero_Dawn__PS4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GovHack 2016 (Little Steps aka MOLE)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/GovHack__MOLE/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 19:58:33 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/GovHack__MOLE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This project will develop a prototype, responsive and visually simple website
that can help newly arrived migrants, refugees and asylum seekers navigate the
complexities of settlement in Australia and connect to communities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the team I was in charge of extracting information from different
data sources, which also involved diverse formats like CSV, plain text and JSON.
Also I implemented an API in Python Flask that was used to query and return
information from our consolidated data source. I was also involved, to a minor
degree, with the UI that was used for the final prototype. The code I developed
is shared through my
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deilanexe/govhack-mole-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatbots and Voice-operated Assistants (Jan 2017 - Present)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Chatbots_and_Voice_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Chatbots_and_Voice_services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since my beginnings in the area of computing, I have been interested in
implementing systems with artificial intelligence that support people in their
everyday lives. Conversational systems was an area that I tapped into during my
PhD research, but not to the extent that I would have liked. However, this has
changed during my stay in Sensis, as we started prototyping some chatbots and
capabilities for users to interact with via voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the prototypes I have worked with include: skills for Amazon Alexa,
actions for Google Home, chatbots for Facebook Messenger and Slack. The
applications implemented range from search capabilities through our Sensis API,
to work-related tasks such as validating input information that we require when
servicing queries from sales representatives regarding our search engine. I have
implemented these capabilities in Python Flask APIs using Natural Language
Understanding platforms such as LUIS, API.ai and recast.ai.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity Rush 2</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/Gravity_Rush_2__PS4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/Gravity_Rush_2__PS4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Fantasy XV</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/Final_Fantasy_XV__PS4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/Final_Fantasy_XV__PS4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last of Us Remastered</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/The_Last_of_Us__PS4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/The_Last_of_Us__PS4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WATCH_DOGS</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/Watch_Dogs__PS4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/dig/Watch_Dogs__PS4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Pages Categorisation (Nov 2016-Present)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/White_Pages_Classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/White_Pages_Classification/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
