<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sensis on My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo</title>
    <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/tags/sensis/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sensis on My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/sensis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Capability program (Oct 2010 - Present)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Search_Capability_program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Search_Capability_program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Search Capability Program has built a heavily-tuned SOLR-based search engine
  currently servicing millions of requests per day, serving up highly relevant
  search results for Business, Government and Points of Interest for Yellow
  Pages, WhereIs (Mobile) and numerous external partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with the SAPI development team, the Search Capability team consists
  primarily of Data Scientists who leverage interaction data and content from
  across Sensis (Yellow Pages, White Pages and WhereIs) to automate the
  measurement and improvement of the SAPI Search algorithm and associated
  Ontologies for a dramatically improved User Experience and Advertiser ROI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensis Ontology Program (Mar 2013 - Jun 2014)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Sensis_Ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Sensis_Ontologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sensis Ontology Program is an enabler for richer classification of Business,
Government and Geospatial content and data across Sensis which aims to move
classification away from manually managed print heading structures and into
automated digital clusters of terms, concepts and categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is designed to assist in providing fresher, more accurate and deeper
content for more accurate retrieval of listings via SAPI Search, but also
provides a significant boost in supporting data for business intelligence and
data science teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also extends on the existing Business Type Search foundation to enable more
granular retrieval of listings based on Brand and Product information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
