<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on My Site</title>
    <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on My Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>SQUAT II (Jul 2016-Present)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/SQUAT_II/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/SQUAT_II/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Search Quality Assessment Tool, or SQUAT, is an internally-developed
framework where search analysts can debug queries to their search platform. In
SQUAT, analysts create &lt;em&gt;gold sets&lt;/em&gt;, which are collections of user &lt;em&gt;queries&lt;/em&gt; with
a set of expected results, also called &lt;em&gt;expectations&lt;/em&gt;. In its second
implementation, SQUAT enables map-based search, gold set result comparisons, and
an API to connect to that provides the endpoints required to operate these
functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my contribution to SQUAT II, I got involved with the redesign of the
user interface, including some of the functional components such as the creation
of gold sets and importing/exporting gold sets into and from spreadsheets for
easy operation outside of the tool. I was also in charge of documenting cards for an offshore
developer who is in charge of implementing these changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQUAT II is likely to have a release outside of Sensis sometime during 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GovHack 2016 (Little Steps aka MOLE)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/GovHack__MOLE/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 19:58:33 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/GovHack__MOLE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This project will develop a prototype, responsive and visually simple website
that can help newly arrived migrants, refugees and asylum seekers navigate the
complexities of settlement in Australia and connect to communities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the team I was in charge of extracting information from different
data sources, which also involved diverse formats like CSV, plain text and JSON.
Also I implemented an API in Python Flask that was used to query and return
information from our consolidated data source. I was also involved, to a minor
degree, with the UI that was used for the final prototype. The code I developed
is shared through my
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deilanexe/govhack-mole-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatbots and Voice-operated services (Jan 2017 - Present)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Chatbots_and_Voice_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Chatbots_and_Voice_services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since my beginnings in the area of computing, I have been interested in
implementing systems with artificial intelligence that support people in their
everyday lives. Conversational systems was an area that I tapped into during my
PhD research, but not to the extent that I would have liked. However, this has
changed during my stay in Sensis, as we started prototyping some chatbots and
capabilities for users to interact with via voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the prototypes I have worked with include: skills for Amazon Alexa,
actions for Google Home, chatbots for Facebook Messenger and Slack. The
applications implemented range from search capabilities through our Sensis API,
to work-related tasks such as validating input information that we require when
servicing queries from sales representatives regarding our search engine. I have
implemented these capabilities in Python Flask APIs using Natural Language
Understanding platforms such as LUIS, API.ai and recast.ai.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RHoK: Changing Places (Jun 2016)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/RHoK__Jun_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/RHoK__Jun_2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rhokaustralia.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Random Hacks of Kindness&lt;/a&gt; is &amp;ldquo;a
community of technologists who solve problems for purpose driven organisations&amp;rdquo;.
In the Winter 2016 2-day hackaton, I joined the team
&lt;a href=&#34;http://changingplaces.org.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Changing Places&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which had the following
tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;completing their WordPress website; and,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proposing new ways for users to interact with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got involved in the second task, and proposed different approaches for fast
communication under the assumption that many carers carry a smart phone with
them. The proposal used Twitter, as well as QR codes to enable such channels.
Our team was the winner team of the hackaton.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Network (Ontology 2.0; Mar-Sep 2016)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Knowledge_Network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Knowledge_Network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the major challenges with the Sensis Ontology program was the scale of
the proof-of-concept system against the final production version, which was
smaller in comparison. Consequently, some of the tasks of the construction
process that were originally implemented sequentially could not be completed
even in finite time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second version of the Sensis Ontology, which was also rebranded as the
&amp;ldquo;Knowledge Network&amp;rdquo;, consisted of re-thinking the original implementation that
produced the database contents as tasks that could be executed in parallel. In
addition to this, we reviewed and simplified some of these tasks to reduce
dependencies and speed up the overall process to produce the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, the process to construct the Knowledge Network passed from infinite
time to less than six months (as with the original PoC), and a ten-fold increase
in performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what-to-wear</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/what-to-wear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/what-to-wear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;what-to-wear&lt;/em&gt; is an application with the purpose of storing my clothes and when
I use them. It is comprised of a frontend developed in HTML, AngularJS and
JavaScript (available on request), and a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deilanexe/what-to-wear-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;backend API in Python Flask&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is mostly a log application with the idea of developing different
skills, my idea is to extend this to implement
machine learning services like proactively suggesting what garments to wear at
a given day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontology Opportunities (Jul 2015 - Jun 2016)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Ontology_Opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Ontology_Opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Sensis Ontology in production, the next step consisted of demonstrating
the capabilities of our product to other business units within Sensis. This
required face-to-face conversations with potential stakeholders, understanding
their pain points and working towards solutions for them that could use our
product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By making a collection of endpoints available within the company, I was able to
ask around the company for potential stakeholders with areas of improvement that
could be addressed by developing quick &amp;ldquo;proof-of-concepts&amp;rdquo;. Some of these
prototypes are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Category Suggestion: As Yellow Pages operates under the existence of
&amp;ldquo;headings&amp;rdquo;, currently the process to assign a heading is manual and requires
expertise of sales representatives on 2000+ categories where businesses can be
classified into. Our PoC uses small snippets of text and information in the
Sensis Ontology for suggesting the best heading an advertiser can appear into in
order to be relevant. This prototype has been tested by different business units
so far and internally within the Search and Knowledge Discovery team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keyword Validation: Another manual process consists of assigning keywords to
advertisers&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Business Profile Pages&lt;/em&gt; that help them distinguish themselves from
their competitors. Our prototype used information available for each advertiser
in the Sensis Ontology to
populate an initial set of relevant keywords. The original concept of this
project has evolved over the past months and will be put into production in
2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Website Leads: As part of the Marketing Acquisition strategy, we implemented
a prototype that collected information from advertisers&amp;rsquo; websites based on
quality display metrics, such as Google&amp;rsquo;s Mobile Friendly Test. This tool was
mostly used as a prototype, but was run as such intermittently over 2016, with
casual specific requests over two more months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Product Search: Sensis Ontology can be used to classify and detect concepts
representing brands, products and services. With classifications openly
available in resources like Wikipedia, we could use these to arrange our
concepts, thus enabling a new search
capability that extends what the Sensis API can currently achieve. Product
Search was tested with data from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skip.com.au&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Skip&lt;/a&gt;, but due to
clashing priorities was never put into production.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Capability program (Oct 2010 - Present)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Search_Capability_program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Search_Capability_program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Search Capability Program has built a heavily-tuned SOLR-based search engine
  currently servicing millions of requests per day, serving up highly relevant
  search results for Business, Government and Points of Interest for Yellow
  Pages, WhereIs (Mobile) and numerous external partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with the SAPI development team, the Search Capability team consists
  primarily of Data Scientists who leverage interaction data and content from
  across Sensis (Yellow Pages, White Pages and WhereIs) to automate the
  measurement and improvement of the SAPI Search algorithm and associated
  Ontologies for a dramatically improved User Experience and Advertiser ROI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensis Ontology Program (Mar 2013 - Jun 2014)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Sensis_Ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Sensis_Ontologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sensis Ontology Program is an enabler for richer classification of Business,
Government and Geospatial content and data across Sensis which aims to move
classification away from manually managed print heading structures and into
automated digital clusters of terms, concepts and categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is designed to assist in providing fresher, more accurate and deeper
content for more accurate retrieval of listings via SAPI Search, but also
provides a significant boost in supporting data for business intelligence and
data science teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also extends on the existing Business Type Search foundation to enable more
granular retrieval of listings based on Brand and Product information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
