<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo</title>
    <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on My Site - Daniel Macias-Galindo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 19:58:33 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>GovHack 2016 (Little Steps aka MOLE)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/GovHack__MOLE/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 19:58:33 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/GovHack__MOLE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This project will develop a prototype, responsive and visually simple website
that can help newly arrived migrants, refugees and asylum seekers navigate the
complexities of settlement in Australia and connect to communities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the team I was in charge of extracting information from different
data sources, which also involved diverse formats like CSV, plain text and JSON.
Also I implemented an API in Python Flask that was used to query and return
information from our consolidated data source. I was also involved, to a minor
degree, with the UI that was used for the final prototype. The code I developed
is shared through my
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deilanexe/govhack-mole-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular 2 Hack (hosted by General Assembly &amp; SSW)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Angular_2_hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Angular_2_hack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I participated in this half-a-day crash-course hosted by General Assembly to
learn the basics on Angular 2. Given that &lt;em&gt;what-to-wear&lt;/em&gt; was a personal project
already running in AngularJS, me and my friend
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ma-al.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mardi&lt;/a&gt; decided to work towards
starting its migration to Angular 2. We struggled a bit to make it work and
reducing dependencies towards using PHP (which set the basis for developing
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deilanexe/what-to-wear-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;what-to-wear API&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
project).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up sharing the top prize as shown
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SSW_TV/status/784639225434107904&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RHoK: Changing Places (Jun 2016)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/RHoK__Jun_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/RHoK__Jun_2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rhokaustralia.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Random Hacks of Kindness&lt;/a&gt; is &amp;ldquo;a
community of technologists who solve problems for purpose driven organisations&amp;rdquo;.
In the Winter 2016 2-day hackaton, I joined the team
&lt;a href=&#34;http://changingplaces.org.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Changing Places&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which had the following
tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;completing their WordPress website; and,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proposing new ways for users to interact with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got involved in the second task, and proposed different approaches for fast
communication under the assumption that many carers carry a smart phone with
them. The proposal used Twitter, as well as QR codes to enable such channels.
Our team was the winner team of the hackaton. Proof of our achievement is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/acd_eddie/status/739345009435017217/photo/1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what-to-wear</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/what-to-wear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/what-to-wear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;what-to-wear&lt;/em&gt; is an application with the purpose of storing my clothes and when
I use them. It is comprised of a frontend developed in HTML, AngularJS and
JavaScript (available on request), and a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/deilanexe/what-to-wear-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;backend API in Python Flask&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is mostly a log application with the idea of developing different
skills, my idea is to extend this to implement
machine learning services like proactively suggesting what garments to wear at
a given day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Capability program (Oct 2010 - Present)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Search_Capability_program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Search_Capability_program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Search Capability Program has built a heavily-tuned SOLR-based search engine
  currently servicing millions of requests per day, serving up highly relevant
  search results for Business, Government and Points of Interest for Yellow
  Pages, WhereIs (Mobile) and numerous external partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with the SAPI development team, the Search Capability team consists
  primarily of Data Scientists who leverage interaction data and content from
  across Sensis (Yellow Pages, White Pages and WhereIs) to automate the
  measurement and improvement of the SAPI Search algorithm and associated
  Ontologies for a dramatically improved User Experience and Advertiser ROI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensis Ontology Program (Mar 2013 - Jun 2014)</title>
      <link>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Sensis_Ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deilanexe.github.io/project/Sensis_Ontologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sensis Ontology Program is an enabler for richer classification of Business,
Government and Geospatial content and data across Sensis which aims to move
classification away from manually managed print heading structures and into
automated digital clusters of terms, concepts and categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is designed to assist in providing fresher, more accurate and deeper
content for more accurate retrieval of listings via SAPI Search, but also
provides a significant boost in supporting data for business intelligence and
data science teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also extends on the existing Business Type Search foundation to enable more
granular retrieval of listings based on Brand and Product information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
